um should you pay for a
book this is a very controversial topic
and I'm going to tell you what I think
and you can agree or
disagree um I think it depends and it
and that's up to you and I'm not going
to tell you what to do but this is what
I would do if I were living in an
economy that was not a part of the
western
economy uh I would not I would not paper
books I would get I would get books
published in the west any way I could
including some ways that would be
considered illegal in the United States
even though the country I'm in would not
be considered illegal you know would I
would I pirate those books if I were if
I lived in an economy in a country that
did not uh that I was not a part of the
western economy it yeah absolutely I
totally would um do I think that's
Justified I personally think that's
Justified there's many people who
disagree
um and I'm just telling you what I would
do um however I am a member of a very
solid Western economy I'm also a white
man in America so you know I have
benefited from all the entitlements that
come from that I don't mean that to be a
political statement I'm just a statement
of fact um I'm very well paid so I pay
for books and I you know I recently paid
$40 for the head for cbook which we're
going to do in the beginner boost and
there's another video about that and I
have no problem doing that and
encouraging people to do that and my
advice is and not advice what I would do
if you are a member of a western economy
and particularly if you're employed then
I think you should I think you should
pay I really do and do I like the system
do I like that people are charging 4050
$100 for a book in Academia that's
absolute crap no I don't like that and
that students are being forced to buy it
so there is one caveat to this or one
exception I'll say um it's I'll tell a
story there there's a university
Professor who shall remain unnamed good
friend uh not really a direct friend
something I've never met but um they
were teaching their students and lit in
their curriculum they literally included
a paragraph that says okay here's the
official play to go get the book and
this is where you're supposed to go get
it and the price tag is something like
$160 for this book it's absolutely
outrageous because they know they have a
monopoly on the book and the people that
the writers who are writing academic
books are writing them for the people
that are going to force them to be
purchased they're not writing them for
the people who are going to do the
learning it's really sad that's just how
it is and and so this professor
professor put a paragraph in their
syllabus that says there are alternative
ways of acquiring this
book which is basically saying if you're
going to Pirate this overpriced piece of
crap academic book with I am forced to
follow because my college says we have
to use it go for it now so again this is
a very personal decision every single
one of you is going to have to make the
decision uh a few people in my chat have
said things that I straight up
categorically disagree with people have
said things like um all books should be
free I disagree with that that's like
saying that
you know everybody should work for free
and and as a content creator and as
somebody who spends a tremendous amount
of time trying to get the perfect
outline or the perfect thing now I don't
charge for any of my content other than
what people can give me and subscribe to
and all that stuff and and I that's for
a different reason which I will talk
about but but to say that all books
should be free I don't agree with that I
don't agree with that that's like saying
that's like saying that you know nobody
should be
paid to be fair if all books could be
free and the authors of those books
could still be could could feed their
families because they were being paid in
some other way sort of like if a teacher
were paid some other way than by the
students as far as the students are
concerned the education is free but the
the people who are providing the
education are still able to feed their
families the the the idea that that
certain professions or certain certain
things um do not warrant uh money makes
me crazy thank you for finding me on
YouTube um and I just want to say that
that really drives me crazy because as
as much as I am a pro open source and a
free free and open source kind of person
you know I draw the line when stalman in
his comparison says if you bring cookies
to school you should share all your
cookies and then he says if you bring
software to school you should give a
copy of your software to
everybody disagree completely 100%
strong disagree with that you there
would be you know in in in a world where
you can't feed your family or you can't
feed yourself unless you are given an
exchange of energy in the form of money
for the stuff that you do telling
someone that what they do has less value
than somebody else because you think it
you should get it for free is wrong and
and I strongly disagree with that um
does that make me a Libertarian or a
communist or capitalist kind of malange
I guess I am because and I've been a
free and open source guy for a very long
time and I I've been I've tell you what
it's it's anyway so books should not be
free if somebody wants to charge for a
book fine now it depends on the
demographic right so let me just
conclude with a story and I'm going to
tell you why my content is free and
strictly speaking it's not free right um
my I have two stories here uh regarding
content and why my content is free and
in with regard to the book thing and whe
where you should get that book and and
how you should do it so the first story
is I received and I already told the
story to everybody on the chat so I'm
going to repeat it um I received a about
a two-page email from somebody in Fiji
um who had gone through my YouTube
stuff and found some of the other thing
and it triggered their own autodidactic
practice and they went from being a
farmer to being a technologist who was
supporting their extended family in Fiji
and they were gushing with gratitude and
and when I heard about that that
solidified the the reason that I didn't
that I didn't do this um another quick
version of the story I had the parent
who was in in the finance industry of of
of a person um tell me that I was
undercharging and that I should try to
Triple for the for the one-on-one
mentoring that I was doing and I said no
because that would prevent a lot of
people from even coming um so I charge
you know piano lesson rates $50 an hour
so my consideration the reason that this
YouTube video is free and and the reason
it's really not right because there's
ads but and the reason that my skill set
that I owe is going to be free and I
probably am not going to do a udemy or
any of that is because I don't want to
raise the bar above the
economy um of people in Fiji or or
Malaysia or wherever they might be who
who want to change um their stars and
what's really unfortunate is is members
of the western economy very frequently
choose not to take advantage of these
resources uh or even worse to devalue
them because they're free one of the
biggest mistakes you could ever make is
to think that because something's free
it's it's not valuable happens all the
time I've been told over and over again
my wife and I we talk about this a lot
my wife is an artist and she's regularly
told you need to quadruple your prices
for your art because if you don't value
it then nobody else is going to Value it
either that might be human nature it
still sucks and I don't believe in it so
I'm not going to raise my because I want
people to feel like they can use the
content I'm also really messy and sloppy
in the production of my content um and
if I were charging you know if I were
going to charge 40 bucks a video or a
book um you know I would I would expect
a certain much higher level of editing
um which unfortunately doesn't exist in
some of these books they're I don't I'm
not going to go there so so pay for the
book pay for the book if you can if
you're in the western economy you make
your own decisions sometimes you can get
a good deal on them um I'll make a
separate video about why I think getting
a tech book is almost always a bad
choice uh there are obvious exceptions
to that but almost always buying a test
a tech book is is is a mistake because
you can get that content someplace else
you just don't know where to go to get
the content um and but that is there are
some very strong exceptions to that and
one of those is the head for c book and
we're going to talk about that so make
sure you watch that video um uh this is
this has been a a very tough um video to
make but the takeaway of the video is um
if you can't pay maybe pay when you can
um but human nature is not pay for
things even when they have the money so
just a reminder if you have the money
you should
pay bye